Garnet Samuels

BSc (Honours)Computer Science with Business Graduate

Coventry, CV2 5GB|Garnet.Samuels@outlook.com|07469955278

https://www.linkedin.com/in/Garnet-Samuels

PERSONAL PROFILE: Graduating from Aston University holding a 2:1 degree classification in BSc (Honours) Computer Science with Business. A highly adaptable and driven individual, who has developed and enhanced their technical and professional skill set in Aston University and polished his soft skills in a variety of work experiences. Problem-solving and ingenuity were vital to my self-development during my studies with the efficient completion of projects and modules using a myriad of programming languages for business use cases. My final year project was titled: Modelling NBA Results with Machine Learning Algorithms: A Comparative Study. This has enhanced my python coding skills as I utilised the Pandas and NumPy libraries, my data science knowledge learning concepts like normalisation and backpropagation for hidden layer weighting for Artificial Neural Networks, and Agile project development skills by working closely with my project supervisor to have weekly project meetings.

KEY SKILLS

Tech-Stack: Python, Java, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, C#, SQL, PHP

Business Skills: Microsoft Power BI, Finance & Economics, Technical Presentation, Sales

Soft skills: Communication, Leadership, Customer Service, Time Management

Certification: can be viewed on my linked in

EDUCATION

September 2019 – June 2023 - Aston University, BSc Computer Science & Business - 2:1 Key Modules: Java Programming Foundation/Java Program Construction (74%) | Mathematics for Computing Professionals (93%) | Information Systems and databases (78%) | Information Security (75%) | Software Lifecycle and design (67%) | Enterprise Computing Strategies (80%) | Technology Practice of eCommerce (70%) | Doing eBusiness (68%) | Economic Environment of Business (78%).

September 2016 – June 2018 - Leventhorpe Sixth Form. Studied Subjects - Computer Science, Business Studies, Physics.

September 2011 - June 2016 - Burnt Mill Academy - 10 GCSE grades.

Optional Subjects: Computer Science, Business Studies, History, Geography

PROJECTS

Final Year Project – Successfully developed Machine Learning Models that Predicted NBA outcomes to 75% accuracy: Modelled machine learning algorithms to predict the outcomes of NBA games using Ridge Regression, Decision Trees, Random Forests, and Neural Networks. Developed skills in data analysis, data science, data engineering, ML engineering, project management, research, problem-solving, and stakeholder management.

Team Project – Successfully created an Online Turn Based PVP Artillery Game: our game was a turn based 2D shooter implemented with Java and Unity where players competed against each other on a multi-client server. Developed, C#, Unity skills, teamwork, communication, delegation skills and time management.

Group Project - Online Business 'eBox': created customisable domain names for businesses where a professional forwarded account delivered business emails to the client's personal account. We also provided web services like website hosting.

Personal Portfolio Website- Web Application – hosted in GitPages and developed using JavaScript, HTML, CSS. My Personal Portfolio display my professional and educational skills and background as well as displaying Front-End Web development skills.

Work Experience

[10/2023 - Present] • Bids Systems Analyst, Veolia:

Being a Bids Systems Analyst has developed my skills in professional networking and requirement gathering with cross functional stakeholders. Performing systems analytics for Veolia's Ecological Transformation services' (Industrial, Water, Energy) digital Solutions/Systems and Products.

- Currently developing an internal standardisation system within the Digital Transformation Team
- Supporting the deployment of client-facing reporting using Microsoft Power BI.
- Lead cross functional point of contact between technical, marketing and sales teams

[07/2023 - 08/2023] • Freelance Salesman, Eco-4:

As a freelance sales role built upon skills in teamwork, delegation, and time management we worked in groups to qualify and complete sales for the government housing energy scheme.

- Identified and qualified clients against the official government approval criteria.
- Created and fostered customer relationships to guarantee a smooth installation and fitting process of energy efficient upgrades
- Resolved customer queries and complaints by being a point of contact throughout the installation and fitting process also recorded data for Eco-4 and contractors.

[06/2022 - 09/2022] • Senior Team Member, Greggs:

My key Senior Team Member responsibilities included: team management, opening and closing the store, stock level management, timesheet management, shift management, and cash flow management.

- Systems used for managerial duties: SAP ERP and SAP SuccessFactors
- Ensured high hygiene levels throughout the entire premises.
- Encouraged and motivated team members to increase efficiency and productivity.

[04/2022-05/2022] • Salesman, Citrine:

Contracted through Citrine as a Salesperson for BT/EE for the technical government initiative of upgrading residential areas to full fibre broadband.

- Worked collaboratively in teams to ensure the best possible performance and sales quotas were met.
- Identified and qualified clients get the products and services that would best suit their network requirements.
- Consulted with clients to understand their ideal network requirements and provide a desirable network service or upgrade with BT/EE

[03/2021 - 01/2022] • Courier, Just Eat Takeaway:

Transported food and drinks from restaurants to customers in a safe and punctual manner.

- Secured and transported collected goods from restaurants to clients .
- Communicated any preparation and or transportation issues that affected the expected service.
- Adherence to food safety policies.

[01/2019 - 08/2020] • Store Manager, Miss Macaroon:

Managed business operations whilst the owner was out-of-store.

- Managerial duties included: sales management, stock management, cash-flow management, and opening/closing the store.
- Ensured balanced working capital for liquid transactions and daily sales targets were met
- Facilitated exceptional customer experiences for; B2B clients, touring groups, and individuals by providing tailored service packages and detailing our social enterprise initiatives to help young people gain skills.

[08/2018 - 01/2019] • Janitor, Inflight Engineering:

Completed janitorial duties to a professional quality.

- Identified and restocked products that needed to be refilled and or reordered.
- Cleaned the communal kitchen and office spaces.
- Ensured all refuse items and materials were disposed of into the right waste containers.

[06/2015] • IT Assistant, Brilliant IT:

Worked on the development of bespoke software and hardware solutions for clients.

• Front-End Web Development

REFERENCES

• Completed invoices for the sales of hardware software and peripherals Products/Solutions and Systems

Volunteering

[01/2012-Feb/2015] • Lead AV Technician, SEC SDA Church:

Managed and operated systems, audio, and visual equipment. My role included: displaying content from multiple sources for presentation with projectors/streaming, recording and broadcasting live events with mics and cameras as well as, mixing and mastering sound with a sound board.

[08/2016] • Gardening, NCS:

I volunteered to maintain and keep the Harlow town park, and town park private garden clean and in good condition over the summer after starting this role during NCS. I worked with a group of other volunteers to plant trees and keep the park clean.